<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Coducer Website</title>
 <link href="http://www.coducer.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.coducer.com/"/>
 <updated>2014-04-12T16:38:42+05:30</updated>
 <id>http://www.coducer.com/</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jai Keerthi</name>
   <email>me@jaikeerthi.in</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>How we handle static websites</title>
   <link href="http://www.coducer.com//blog/how-we-handle-static-websites.html"/>
   <updated>2011-10-03T00:00:00+05:30</updated>
   <id>http://www.coducer.com/blog/how_we_handle_with_websites</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;We at coducer uses right technologies in right place. we try to make our code dry(do not repeat yourself) as possible as we can. We strictly follow code conventions, we belive good code make our project maintainable. We prefer following these stratagies would help us to develop a web site quicker and maintainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;static_site_generator&#39;&gt;Static site generator:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static site generators are fast easy to configure, use and deploy of different environment. There are few advantages in static site generators,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     1. Fast and easy to cache (Files are generated when application starts)
     2. Safe to use, no code executes on server.
     3. Easy to version control(git, svn), so regenerate it to its past at any time.
     4. Easy to extend, most of static site generators are opensource and you can extend it for your needs.
     5. These are available for most of the programming languages( Ruby: jekyll, PHP: phrozn, Node.js: petrify, more...)
     6. Easy to maintain for long term&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;css_frameworks&#39;&gt;CSS Frameworks:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A CSS framework is a library that is meant to allow for easier, more standards-compliant styling of a webpage using the Cascading Style Sheets language. Just like programming and scripting language libraries, CSS frameworks package a number of ready-made options for designing and outlaying a webpage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     1. Eleminates lots of Browser dependencies.
     2. Grid structure helps to solve lots of complex layouts(both liquid and fixed style).
     3. Builtin methods helps to implement browser independent styles.
     4. Plugins available for lots of features like css-sprites
     5. Also works well in css 3, sass, scss
     6. Widely used frameworks are Blueprint, 960 Grid System.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#39;version_control&#39;&gt;Version Control:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Version control system helps to maintain collection of files created over time. It helps to go back to previous verion of an individual time, also allows to compare any version of files and differentiate their changes. It gives us an advantage of getting back to previous instance of code at any time. We prefer working on git because,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;     1. Free and opensource.
     2. Everything is local.
     3. Fast, small and distributed.
     4. Easy to learn.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
